<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rotational Labs</title><link>https://rotational.io/</link><description>Recent content on Rotational Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; {year} Rotational Labs, Inc &amp;middot; All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 10:21:41 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rotational.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ensign for Enterprise AI</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/ensign-for-enterprise-ai/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 07:29:49 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/ensign-for-enterprise-ai/</guid><description>&lt;p>These days nearly every tech exec is thinking about how to bring AI and automation to the enterprise. Use cases vary, but all rely on one thing — a data management layer to connect and coordinate data across the organization.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mocking the Universe: Two Techniques for Testing gRPC with Mocks</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/mocking-the-universe/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 13:29:11 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/mocking-the-universe/</guid><description>&lt;p>At Rotational, &lt;a href="https://rotational.io/blog/what-are-protocol-buffers/">we use gRPC&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://rotational.io/blog/documenting-grpc-with-openapi">quite a bit&lt;/a>. It&amp;rsquo;s great for specifying network APIs, but can challenge us to find new ways to thoroughly test the code. Follow along with this post to learn two ways of using &lt;a href="https://rotational.io/blog/fake-it-when-you-make-it/">mocking&lt;/a> to test gRPC services!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mastering the Art of Data Freshness</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/mastering-the-art-of-data-freshness/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 10:34:25 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/mastering-the-art-of-data-freshness/</guid><description>&lt;p>Two decades ago Clive Humby proclaimed &amp;ldquo;data is the new oil&amp;rdquo;, marking an economic shift towards data products. But, if the intervening years have taught us anything, it&amp;rsquo;s to think of data more like fresh fruit.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Introducing Ensign</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/introducing-ensign/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 10:32:35 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/introducing-ensign/</guid><description>&lt;p>Have you always wanted to build an event-driven system, but couldn’t justify spending the cognitive overhead or platform engineering costs? Introducing Ensign &amp;ndash; eventing made easy!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Double-Checked Locking</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/double-checked-locking/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 12:31:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/double-checked-locking/</guid><description>&lt;p>Double-checked locking is a common mechanism to avoid race conditions when using read and write locks. Unfortunately, as with nearly all things related to concurrency, it is easy to get wrong or forget.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Everything I Know About Project Management I Learned From Cattle Ranching</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/wrangling-cattle-and-engineers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 16:11:27 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/wrangling-cattle-and-engineers/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you think farmwork and software don&amp;rsquo;t have much in common, think again!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Building a Raft (Part 3)</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/building-a-raft-part-3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 12:24:32 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/building-a-raft-part-3/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the third and final part of our series exploring the popular consensus algorithm we&amp;rsquo;ll finally explore how Raft handles leader election, and in doing so discover how Raft is so incredibly resilient.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Prototyping Event-Driven Applications With Watermill</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/prototyping-eda-with-watermill/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 11:13:46 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/prototyping-eda-with-watermill/</guid><description>&lt;p>Event-driven architectures (EDA) are &lt;a href="https://rotational.io/blog/five-technologies-quietly-transforming-the-web/">enjoying a resurgence in interest&lt;/a> due to many organizations&amp;rsquo; need to accelerate rapid prototyping and get by with smaller, more cross-functional teams. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll demonstrate how to get started prototyping EDAs with the open source package Watermill.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Building a Raft (Part 2)</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/building-a-raft-part-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 09:55:04 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/building-a-raft-part-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>In our first installment on how to implement the famous Raft algorithm, we introduced the log: an ordered sequence of operations that serves as the core data structure for distributed consensus. In this second part, we&amp;rsquo;ll demonstrate the beating heart of Raft, which is log replication.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>3 Trends that Will Disrupt Managed Services in 2023</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/disrupt-managed-services/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 11:43:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/disrupt-managed-services/</guid><description>&lt;p>If nothing else, the last year has brought the winds of change to the tech sector. From high-visibility &lt;a href="https://layoffs.fyi/">layoff cycles&lt;/a> at FAANGs and crypto companies, to turbulence in our &lt;a href="https://rotational.io/blog/twitter-wont-disappear-overnight/">social media infrastructure&lt;/a>, to pop culture&amp;rsquo;s discovery of deep learning products like AI art and ChatGPT.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But many of us in tech are beginning to sense even bigger, deeper rumblings that suggest some fundamental changes afoot for commercial cloud and managed services. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore three: (1) native observability, (2) cost-effective scaling, and (3) self-orchestration.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Building a Raft (Part 1)</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/building-a-raft-part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 17:14:04 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/building-a-raft-part-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>With all the &lt;a href="https://rotational.io/blog/six-things-you-didnt-know-about-crypto/">blockchain breaches&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://rotational.io/blog/twitter-wont-disappear-overnight/">social media escapades&lt;/a>, there&amp;rsquo;s been an awful lot of buzz about distributed systems lately. But how many of us really understand how they work? Let&amp;rsquo;s dive in together&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ensign</title><link>https://rotational.io/ensign/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 10:09:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/ensign/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Choosing Serialization Formats in Go</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/go-serialization-formats/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 10:27:11 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/go-serialization-formats/</guid><description>&lt;p>Serialization format is an often-overlooked engineering step that could make your application as slow as a turtle or as speedy as a cheetah!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>No, Twitter Won't Disappear Overnight</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/twitter-wont-disappear-overnight/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 16:52:09 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/twitter-wont-disappear-overnight/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this post we&amp;rsquo;ll explore the question, how does a distributed system &lt;em>actually&lt;/em> die?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>October Retreats and Conferences</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/october-retreats-and-conferences/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 13:32:04 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/october-retreats-and-conferences/</guid><description>&lt;p>Even though we are a fully distributed team, we celebrate curiosity, collaboration, and growth together in-person as much as we can. We&amp;rsquo;ve maintained a tradition of combining tech conferences with team retreats, and this October we had our second 2022 retreat in Chicago, Illinois collocated with &lt;a href="https://www.gophercon.com/home">GopherCon 2022&lt;/a>. We also attended &lt;a href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/kubecon-cloudnativecon-north-america/">KubeCon 2022&lt;/a> in Detroit at the end of the month.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Privacy Policy</title><link>https://rotational.io/privacy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 11:44:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/privacy/</guid><description>This Privacy Policy governs the manner in which Rotational Labs, LLC collects, uses, maintains and discloses information collected from users (each, a &amp;ldquo;User&amp;rdquo;) of the https://rotational.</description></item><item><title>Terms and Conditions</title><link>https://rotational.io/terms/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 11:44:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/terms/</guid><description>Last updated: October 14, 2022</description></item><item><title>Services</title><link>https://rotational.io/services/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 12:40:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/services/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Opensource</title><link>https://rotational.io/opensource/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 17:16:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/opensource/</guid><description/></item><item><title>About Us</title><link>https://rotational.io/about/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 15:01:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/about/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Contact Us</title><link>https://rotational.io/contact/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 15:01:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/contact/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Why WebAssembly Is the Future of Computing</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/webassembly-the-future-of-computing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 08:51:27 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/webassembly-the-future-of-computing/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>If you talk about WebAssembly (WASM), you just may spark debate about whether it is really the next best thing in web development or the second coming of Java applets. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll dive into WASM, how it is currently transforming web development, and why we think its future is so bright.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Eventing Platform Landscape</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/eventing-platforms/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 12:28:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/eventing-platforms/</guid><description>&lt;p>Kafka and PubSub and Kinesis, oh my! Which eventing platform is best? In this post we&amp;rsquo;ll explore the three primary categories of eventing systems and understand their similarities, differences, and key use cases.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ranges of Integer Data Types</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/ranges-of-integer-data-types/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 09:40:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/ranges-of-integer-data-types/</guid><description>&lt;p>The data type choices we make when building data systems or metrics is critically important: as our systems run for long periods of time it can be easy to overflow the integers that we use (Y2K bug anyone?). As a result, I find myself constantly checking the sizes of standard int types but I haven&amp;rsquo;t found a good way to Google this. This blog post is a quick reference for the standard sizes and a discussion on why it matters.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>In Which an English Major Interns in Tech</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/english-major-interns-in-tech/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 06:10:14 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/english-major-interns-in-tech/</guid><description>&lt;p>Over the course of the past few months, I’ve had the pleasure of interning at Rotational Labs as a technical writer. I’m excited to share a little bit about my experience and provide some insight from the perspective of someone who is entering the world of distributed systems for the first time.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Effective Programmers Read Code</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/effective-programmers-read-code/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 08:10:14 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/effective-programmers-read-code/</guid><description>&lt;p>As programmers, we tend think of ourselves as &lt;em>authors&lt;/em> of code, but our daily engineering practice probably requires us to spend more time reading code than writing it. Perhaps this is even a source of stress for you. Changing your mindset to think of yourself as an avid code &lt;em>reader&lt;/em> may not only alleviate this anxiety, but also make you a more effective programmer, capable of architecting complex mental maps of code, a technique I refer to as &amp;ldquo;building the glass castle&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Transparently Mocking gRPC Services</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/transparently-mocking-grpc-services/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 09:32:01 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/transparently-mocking-grpc-services/</guid><description>&lt;p>gRPC is an effective way of implementing service-to-service APIs. However, there are limited tools available for mocking and testing gRPC services out of the box. One option is to set up a live test server, although this comes with its own challenges and costs. In this blog post we will demonstrate a more lightweight solution using the &lt;code>bufconn&lt;/code> package and a hand-built mock. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, this is easier than it seems!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Five Technologies Quietly Transforming the Web</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/five-technologies-quietly-transforming-the-web/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 13:00:01 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/five-technologies-quietly-transforming-the-web/</guid><description>&lt;p>With almost 30 billion connected devices, this isn’t Al Gore’s internet anymore.
Consider this: According to &lt;a href="https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/solutions/collateral/executive-perspectives/annual-internet-report/white-paper-c11-741490.html">Cisco’s Annual Internet Report&lt;/a>, there will be 29.3 billion internet-connected devices in 2023, or more than three for every human. The internet has no doubt transformed society and industry, while proving to be resilient and scalable. It also continues to evolve.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>6 Things You Didn't Realize about Crypto</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/six-things-you-didnt-know-about-crypto/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 09:53:22 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/six-things-you-didnt-know-about-crypto/</guid><description>&lt;p>As a distributed systems company, we’ve had the privilege of speaking with dozens of vendors building crypto-adjacent solutions over the past few years. We’ve learned a lot along the way, especially about some of the key misconceptions that continue to challenge builders, users, investors, and other crypto stakeholders.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Marshaling Go Enums to and from JSON</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/marshaling-go-enums-to-and-from-json/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 08:50:04 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/marshaling-go-enums-to-and-from-json/</guid><description>&lt;p>Customizing JSON serialization for your data types seems relatively straightforward on the surface, but it&amp;rsquo;s easy to get turned around in receiver, value, pointer, and indirection confusion. Many of the patterns and rules-of-thumb you use in your normal Go code can lead you astray. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll illustrate exactly how and why to handle these edge cases.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Achieving Total Ordering With CRDTs</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/achieving-total-ordering-with-crdts/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 15:02:21 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/achieving-total-ordering-with-crdts/</guid><description>&lt;p>Conflict-free replicated data types (or &amp;ldquo;CRDTs&amp;rdquo;) are inspiring the creation of more collaborative applications and improving the experience of users of distributed systems. In this post, we will explore how these data structures can be used to achieve a consistent, total ordering of events across many peers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Getting Started With Tmux</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/getting-started-with-tmux/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 09:41:51 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/getting-started-with-tmux/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you’re working in distributed systems, having a good terminal setup is pretty important! On MacOS &lt;a href="https://iterm2.com/">iTerm2&lt;/a> is a popular choice. It has tabs, autocomplete, a built-in password manager and a fantastic screen splitting feature. If however you’re like me and aren’t using a Mac it can be difficult to find a replacement that fits your needs. Tmux is here to help!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Data Curation: A Whale of a Problem</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/data-curation-baleen/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 11:37:43 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/data-curation-baleen/</guid><description>&lt;p>Once you become an AI/ML practitioner, you quickly realize that the machine learning work is often the &lt;em>least&lt;/em> challenging step in the pipeline. So what&amp;rsquo;s still really, really hard? Getting good data! In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore why that is and introduce a new open source tool for data curation, Baleen.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Translation Monitoring for I18n Projects</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/trans-monitor-i18n-proj/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 19:25:35 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/trans-monitor-i18n-proj/</guid><description>&lt;p>Developing applications for global users usually requires an internationalization (i18n) process that translates contents or user messages into different languages. Given how manual these process tend to be, the more we can automate the better &amp;ndash; for our sanity, for our wallets, and for our users. That&amp;rsquo;s where Rumi comes in!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fake It When You Make It: Creating Mocks in Go</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/fake-it-when-you-make-it/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 10:39:45 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/fake-it-when-you-make-it/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the age of microservices and containerized applications, software is less monolithic and more interdependent. How do we write tests which account for this new reality? One common strategy is to create mocks for services. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore some of the challenges with testing in Go and dive into some concrete examples where creating mocks can help alleviate these problems.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Predicting Star Ratings: Sentiment Analysis Built on MongoDB</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/predicting-star-ratings/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 10:40:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/predicting-star-ratings/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you want to build a robust machine learning model, the most important ingredient is data &amp;ndash; but keep in mind that tuning your model will rely on devising a systematic way to store and query that data! In this post, we explore a project to understand a large dataset of Amazon reviews and predict start ratings using open source sentiment analyzers and the MongoDB ecosystem.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why Developers Don't Translate The Docs</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/why-devs-dont-translate/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 20:25:35 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/why-devs-dont-translate/</guid><description>&lt;p>Stars, forks, likes, upvotes, downloads. In a world where user metrics rule, why don&amp;rsquo;t more technical projects translate their docs to reach more global users?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Introducing Whisper</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/introducing-whisper/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 16:32:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/introducing-whisper/</guid><description>&lt;p>Imagine you have a new engineer joining your team and you need to provide passwords for access to critical systems. Or you need to send a sensitive file to a client. Or you need to share encryption keys with a team member. What do you do?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Data Privacy Regulatory Landscape (as of August 2021)</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/data-privacy-laws/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 17:32:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/data-privacy-laws/</guid><description>&lt;p>Data privacy regulations are gaining traction domestically and internationally. Business and tech leaders would do well to take notice and re-consider their approach to privacy. Here&amp;rsquo;s a synopsis of the latest regulations taking effect or up for consideration.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A History of the Cloud and Where It's Going Next</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/cloud-generations/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 15:32:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/cloud-generations/</guid><description>&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s no doubt public cloud providers have transformed the technology landscape; in this post we retrace the evolution of the cloud to gather clues into where the industry is headed next.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why UX Will Get Worse Before it Gets Better</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/ux-whats-missing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 17:20:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/ux-whats-missing/</guid><description>&lt;p>The things we make are not user-friendly by accident; we have to &lt;em>make&lt;/em> them that way. And that&amp;rsquo;s hard. For most of the time people have been making things, we&amp;rsquo;ve been mainly concerned with making them user-friendly for just &lt;em>us&lt;/em>. And, even if the last few decades of app development have brought more focus to the importance of empathy (especially if it helps you capture market share), the last few years have forced app developers to acknowledge the continued pervasiveness of white privilege, gender privilege, and class privilege in UI/UX. Unfortunately, as our efforts to become more intentional and empathetic as technologists continue in the coming years, there is another problem we have barely considered that will become a major threat to compassionate, egalitarian, and even subversive app development. Spoiler: it&amp;rsquo;s our cloud infrastructure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using Google's Secret Manager API with Go</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/secrets-manager-with-go/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 08:26:38 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/secrets-manager-with-go/</guid><description>&lt;p>Security is by definition an inconvenience. At the very least, it&amp;rsquo;s about making access to data as challenging as possible for the baddies, conveniently measured in computation time. But good security also requires us good folks to go above and beyond — adopting architectural and engineering practices that involve more forethought, more effort, and more testing than are strictly required to get a basic application running on the web. If you&amp;rsquo;re here already, we don&amp;rsquo;t need to convince you that the effort is well worth it; good security pays for itself in customer trust, not to mention helping to preclude the kinds of breaches that can get careless folks in hot water. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll dive into Google&amp;rsquo;s Secret Manager service, walk through the setup steps, and explore some Go code to interact with the API.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What Are Protocol Buffers?</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/what-are-protocol-buffers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 11:05:32 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/what-are-protocol-buffers/</guid><description>&lt;p>Protocol buffers are a method for serializing data to efficiently send between programs. The structure is reminiscent of XML or JSON, but unlike these more commonly used text-based serialization methods, protocol buffers are designed to produce extremely compact messages using a binary format. The main tradeoff is that protocol buffers aren&amp;rsquo;t human-readable, so when developing APIs, it&amp;rsquo;s always important to consider the use case. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore some of the use cases for protobufs and get to know the syntax.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Contexts in Go Microservice Chains</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/contexts-in-go-microservice-chains/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 14:24:33 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/contexts-in-go-microservice-chains/</guid><description>&lt;p>Contexts are a critical part of services implemented in Golang. Although we see them often in server interfaces, they can be mysterious to developers implementing request handlers. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss what contexts are and take a look at a specific example where contexts shine: services that are implemented as a series of microservice requests. Then we&amp;rsquo;ll dive into the tl;dr of contexts — namely, the two crucial rules that all service handlers should implement. Finally, we&amp;rsquo;ll demonstrate a quick experiment using gRPC to show how context deadlines are propagated to downstream microservices during request processing, enabling effective coordination.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Can't Read, Won't Buy</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/cant-read-wont-buy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 11:24:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/cant-read-wont-buy/</guid><description>&lt;p>To say we are not at our most empowered when trying to communicate in an unfamiliar language is a bit of an understatement. As if the limitations of one&amp;rsquo;s own language weren&amp;rsquo;t bad enough, trying to get along in a different language often makes you feel downright &lt;em>helpless&lt;/em>. Research suggests these feelings also strongly inform consumers&amp;rsquo; buying decisions. What does this mean for companies who want to connect with users in other countries and cultures? In this post we&amp;rsquo;ll explore some of the drawbacks of using English-only as a sales medium, check out some creative solutions, and consider what this all means for global app development.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Distributed Systems Maze</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/a-distributed-systems-maze/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 13:49:57 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/a-distributed-systems-maze/</guid><description>&lt;p>The most exciting applications coming out these days are the ones that aim big — aspiring to reach a global audience of users across regions, languages, timezones, and data centers. Not only are they in the exhilarating position of owning planet-scale markets, they&amp;rsquo;re poised to take on some of the most interesting data systems problems we&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Project Planning With Block Based Dependencies</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/project-planning-with-block-based-dependencies/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 07:49:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/project-planning-with-block-based-dependencies/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Good software development achieves complexity by describing the interactions of simple components. Of course, this is harder than it sounds, and if Mark Twain had been a software developer he would have likely said: &amp;ldquo;if I had more time, I would have created a simpler design.&amp;rdquo; This feels even more true at the start of a project when a roadmap has to be laid out and time and cost estimates applied.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Parrot Trainer Eats Crow</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/a-parrot-trainer-eats-crow/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 08:42:21 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/a-parrot-trainer-eats-crow/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll consider how it is that models trained on massive datasets using millions of parameters can be both &amp;ldquo;low bias&amp;rdquo; and also &lt;em>very biased&lt;/em>, and begin to think through what we in the ML community might be able to do about it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Documenting a gRPC API with OpenAPI</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/documenting-grpc-with-openapi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 17:45:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/documenting-grpc-with-openapi/</guid><description>&lt;p>gRPC makes the specification and implementation of networked APIs a snap. But what is the simplest way to &lt;em>document&lt;/em> a gRPC API? There seem to be some hosted providers by Google, e.g. &lt;a href="https://cloud.google.com/endpoints/docs/grpc/dev-portal-update-ref-docs">SmartDocs&lt;/a>, but I have yet to find a gRPC-specific tool. For REST API frameworks, documentation is commonly generated along with live examples using &lt;a href="https://swagger.io/resources/open-api/">OpenAPI (formerly swagger)&lt;/a>. By using &lt;a href="https://github.com/grpc-ecosystem/grpc-gateway">grpc-gateway&lt;/a> it appears to be pretty straight forward to generate a REST/gRPC API combo from protocol buffers and then hook into the OpenAPI specification.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hello World</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 16:20:18 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/hello-world/</guid><description>&lt;p>Right now only half the world is awake. For successful planetary-scale networking, it&amp;rsquo;s time for diurnal intelligently distributed systems.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://rotational.io/bio/beci-lambrecht/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/bio/beci-lambrecht/</guid><description>Beci works to support project management tasks at Rotational Labs through organization, workflow analysis, and communication.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://rotational.io/bio/benjamin-bengfort/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/bio/benjamin-bengfort/</guid><description>Dr. Benjamin Bengfort is co-founder and CEO of Rotational Labs.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://rotational.io/bio/cletus-razakou/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/bio/cletus-razakou/</guid><description>Cletus Razakou is a Senior Front-end engineer at Rotational Labs.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://rotational.io/bio/daniel-sollis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/bio/daniel-sollis/</guid><description>Daniel Sollis is a Junior Distributed Systems Engineer working at Rotational Labs.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://rotational.io/bio/danielle-maxwell/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/bio/danielle-maxwell/</guid><description>Danielle Maxwell is a Junior Distributed Systems Engineer at Rotational Labs.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://rotational.io/bio/edwin-schmierer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/bio/edwin-schmierer/</guid><description>Edwin Schmierer is co-founder and COO of Rotational Labs.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://rotational.io/bio/elysee-bleu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/bio/elysee-bleu/</guid><description>Elysee Bleu is a Junior front-end developer with over 2 years of experience.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://rotational.io/bio/karen-belita/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/bio/karen-belita/</guid><description>Karen Belita is an engineer who brings experience from the data analysis and machine learning domains.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://rotational.io/bio/nabiha-naqvie/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/bio/nabiha-naqvie/</guid><description>Nabiha Naqvie is a data scientist with a background in molecular biology and an interest in Data Engineering, Applied Natural Language Processing and Distributed Systems.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://rotational.io/bio/natasha-white/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/bio/natasha-white/</guid><description>Natasha White is a technical writer and college student with rather intimidating volleyball skills.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://rotational.io/bio/patrick-deziel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/bio/patrick-deziel/</guid><description>Patrick Deziel is a distributed systems engineer and machine learning specialist.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://rotational.io/bio/pete-keleher/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/bio/pete-keleher/</guid><description>Dr. Peter Keleher is a professor in the Computer Science department at University of Maryland.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://rotational.io/bio/prema-roman/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/bio/prema-roman/</guid><description>Prema Roman is a distributed systems engineer at Rotational Labs.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://rotational.io/bio/rebecca-bilbro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/bio/rebecca-bilbro/</guid><description>Dr. Rebecca Bilbro a data scientist, Python and Go programmer, teacher, speaker, and author who has worked in numerous startups from public sector to media &amp;amp; entertainment to enterprise security.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://rotational.io/bio/tianshu-li/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/bio/tianshu-li/</guid><description>Tianshu Li is a data scientist and NLP specialist with a PhD in Systems Engineering and an enduring curiosity for learning, open source, and new culinary adventures.</description></item></channel></rss>