<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rotational Labs</title><link>https://rotational.io/</link><description>Recent content on Rotational Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; 2021 Rotational Labs, LLC, All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 15:02:21 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rotational.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Achieving Total Ordering With CRDTs</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/achieving-total-ordering-with-crdts/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 15:02:21 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/achieving-total-ordering-with-crdts/</guid><description>&lt;p>Conflict-free replicated data types (or &amp;ldquo;CRDTs&amp;rdquo;) are inspiring the creation of more collaborative applications and improving the experience of users of distributed systems. In this post, we will explore how these data structures can be used to achieve a consistent, total ordering of events across many peers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Getting Started With Tmux</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/getting-started-with-tmux/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 09:41:51 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/getting-started-with-tmux/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you’re working in distributed systems, having a good terminal setup is pretty important! On MacOS &lt;a href="https://iterm2.com/">iTerm2&lt;/a> is a popular choice. It has tabs, autocomplete, a built-in password manager and a fantastic screen splitting feature. If however you’re like me and aren’t using a Mac it can be difficult to find a replacement that fits your needs. Tmux is here to help!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Data Curation: A Whale of a Problem</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/data-curation-baleen/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 11:37:43 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/data-curation-baleen/</guid><description>&lt;p>Once you become an AI/ML practitioner, you quickly realize that the machine learning work is often the &lt;em>least&lt;/em> challenging step in the pipeline. So what&amp;rsquo;s still really, really hard? Getting good data! In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore why that is and introduce a new open source tool for data curation, Baleen.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Translation Monitoring for I18n Projects</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/trans-monitor-i18n-proj/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 19:25:35 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/trans-monitor-i18n-proj/</guid><description>&lt;p>Developing applications for global users usually requires an internationalization (i18n) process that translates contents or user messages into different languages. Given how manual these process tend to be, the more we can automate the better &amp;ndash; for our sanity, for our wallets, and for our users. That&amp;rsquo;s where Rumi comes in!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fake It When You Make It: Creating Mocks in Go</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/fake-it-when-you-make-it/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 10:39:45 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/fake-it-when-you-make-it/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the age of microservices and containerized applications, software is less monolithic and more interdependent. How do we write tests which account for this new reality? One common strategy is to create mocks for services. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore some of the challenges with testing in Go and dive into some concrete examples where creating mocks can help alleviate these problems.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Predicting Star Ratings: Sentiment Analysis Built on MongoDB</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/predicting-star-ratings/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 10:40:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/predicting-star-ratings/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you want to build a robust machine learning model, the most important ingredient is data &amp;ndash; but keep in mind that tuning your model will rely on devising a systematic way to store and query that data! In this post, we explore a project to understand a large dataset of Amazon reviews and predict start ratings using open source sentiment analyzers and the MongoDB ecosystem.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why Developers Don't Translate The Docs</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/why-devs-dont-translate/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 20:25:35 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/why-devs-dont-translate/</guid><description>&lt;p>Stars, forks, likes, upvotes, downloads. In a world where user metrics rule, why don&amp;rsquo;t more technical projects translate their docs to reach more global users?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Introducing Whisper</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/introducing-whisper/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 16:32:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/introducing-whisper/</guid><description>&lt;p>Imagine you have a new engineer joining your team and you need to provide passwords for access to critical systems. Or you need to send a sensitive file to a client. Or you need to share encryption keys with a team member. What do you do?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Data Privacy Regulatory Landscape (as of August 2021)</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/data-privacy-laws/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 17:32:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/data-privacy-laws/</guid><description>Data privacy regulations are gaining traction domestically and internationally. Business and tech leaders would do well to take notice and re-consider their approach to privacy.</description></item><item><title>A History of the Cloud and Where It's Going Next</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/cloud-generations/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 15:32:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/cloud-generations/</guid><description>There&amp;rsquo;s no doubt public cloud providers have transformed the technology landscape; in this post we retrace the evolution of the cloud to gather clues into where the industry is headed next.</description></item><item><title>Why UX Will Get Worse Before it Gets Better</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/ux-whats-missing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 17:20:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/ux-whats-missing/</guid><description>The things we make are not user-friendly by accident; we have to make them that way.</description></item><item><title>Using Google's Secret Manager API with Go</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/secrets-manager-with-go/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 08:26:38 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/secrets-manager-with-go/</guid><description>Security is by definition an inconvenience. At the very least, it&amp;rsquo;s about making access to data as challenging as possible for the baddies, conveniently measured in computation time.</description></item><item><title>What Are Protocol Buffers?</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/what-are-protocol-buffers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 11:05:32 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/what-are-protocol-buffers/</guid><description>Protocol buffers are a method for serializing data to efficiently send between programs. The structure is reminiscent of XML or JSON, but unlike these more commonly used text-based serialization methods, protocol buffers are designed to produce extremely compact messages using a binary format.</description></item><item><title>Contexts in Go Microservice Chains</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/contexts-in-go-microservice-chains/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 14:24:33 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/contexts-in-go-microservice-chains/</guid><description>Contexts are a critical part of services implemented in Golang. Although we see them often in server interfaces, they can be mysterious to developers implementing request handlers.</description></item><item><title>Can't Read, Won't Buy</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/cant-read-wont-buy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 11:24:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/cant-read-wont-buy/</guid><description>To say we are not at our most empowered when trying to communicate in an unfamiliar language is a bit of an understatement.</description></item><item><title>A Distributed Systems Maze</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/a-distributed-systems-maze/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 13:49:57 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/a-distributed-systems-maze/</guid><description>The most exciting applications coming out these days are the ones that aim big — aspiring to reach a global audience of users across regions, languages, timezones, and data centers.</description></item><item><title>Project Planning With Block Based Dependencies</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/project-planning-with-block-based-dependencies/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 07:49:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/project-planning-with-block-based-dependencies/</guid><description>Good software development achieves complexity by describing the interactions of simple components. Of course, this is harder than it sounds, and if Mark Twain had been a software developer he would have likely said: &amp;ldquo;if I had more time, I would have created a simpler design.</description></item><item><title>A Parrot Trainer Eats Crow</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/a-parrot-trainer-eats-crow/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 08:42:21 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/a-parrot-trainer-eats-crow/</guid><description>In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll consider how it is that models trained on massive datasets using millions of parameters can be both &amp;ldquo;low bias&amp;rdquo; and also very biased, and begin to think through what we in the ML community might be able to do about it.</description></item><item><title>Documenting a gRPC API with OpenAPI</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/documenting-grpc-with-openapi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 17:45:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/documenting-grpc-with-openapi/</guid><description>gRPC makes the specification and implementation of networked APIs a snap. But what is the simplest way to document a gRPC API?</description></item><item><title>Hello World</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 16:20:18 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/hello-world/</guid><description>Right now only half the world is awake. For successful planetary-scale networking, it&amp;rsquo;s time for diurnal intelligently distributed systems.</description></item><item><title>Benjamin Bengfort</title><link>https://rotational.io/author/benjamin-bengfort/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/author/benjamin-bengfort/</guid><description>Founder and CEO, Rotational Labs, LLC.
Creator of Yellowbrick, machine learning practitioner, distributed systems developer, data science educator, O’Reilly author, Guyanese-American, BBQ enthusiast</description></item><item><title>Daniel Sollis</title><link>https://rotational.io/author/daniel-sollis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/author/daniel-sollis/</guid><description>Junior Software Engineer at Rotational Labs, LLC, focusing on distributed systems.
Python and Go programmer, Cal State Fullerton graduate, David Lynch obsessive and mediocre guitar player.</description></item><item><title>Edwin Schmierer</title><link>https://rotational.io/author/edwin-schmierer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/author/edwin-schmierer/</guid><description>Founder and COO, Rotational Labs, LLC.</description></item><item><title>Nabiha Naqvie</title><link>https://rotational.io/author/nabiha-naqvie/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/author/nabiha-naqvie/</guid><description>Data scientist with a background in molecular biology and an interest in applied Natural Language Processing and Distributed Systems.</description></item><item><title>Patrick Deziel</title><link>https://rotational.io/author/patrick-deziel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/author/patrick-deziel/</guid><description>Distributed Systems Engineer
Python and Go programmer, machine learning enthusiast, sci-fi addict.</description></item><item><title>Rebecca Bilbro</title><link>https://rotational.io/author/rebecca-bilbro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/author/rebecca-bilbro/</guid><description>Founder and CTO, Rotational Labs, LLC.
Creator of Yellowbrick, applied NLP developer, Python &amp;amp; Go programmer, data science educator, O’Reilly author, bad ukulelist.</description></item><item><title>Star Streaks</title><link>https://rotational.io/starstreak/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/starstreak/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Tianshu Li</title><link>https://rotational.io/author/tianshu-li/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/author/tianshu-li/</guid><description>Data scientist and NLP specialist with a PhD in Systems Engineering and an enduring curiosity for learning, open source, and new culinary adventures.</description></item></channel></rss>