<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>i18n on Rotational Labs</title><link>https://rotational.io/tags/i18n/</link><description>Recent content in i18n on Rotational Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 19:25:35 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rotational.io/tags/i18n/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Translation Monitoring for I18n Projects</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/trans-monitor-i18n-proj/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 19:25:35 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/trans-monitor-i18n-proj/</guid><description>&lt;p>Developing applications for global users usually requires an internationalization (i18n) process that translates contents or user messages into different languages. Given how manual these process tend to be, the more we can automate the better &amp;ndash; for our sanity, for our wallets, and for our users. That&amp;rsquo;s where Rumi comes in!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why Developers Don't Translate The Docs</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/why-devs-dont-translate/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 20:25:35 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/why-devs-dont-translate/</guid><description>&lt;p>Stars, forks, likes, upvotes, downloads. In a world where user metrics rule, why don&amp;rsquo;t more technical projects translate their docs to reach more global users?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Can't Read, Won't Buy</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/cant-read-wont-buy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 11:24:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/cant-read-wont-buy/</guid><description>&lt;p>To say we are not at our most empowered when trying to communicate in an unfamiliar language is a bit of an understatement. As if the limitations of one&amp;rsquo;s own language weren&amp;rsquo;t bad enough, trying to get along in a different language often makes you feel downright &lt;em>helpless&lt;/em>. Research suggests these feelings also strongly inform consumers&amp;rsquo; buying decisions. What does this mean for companies who want to connect with users in other countries and cultures? In this post we&amp;rsquo;ll explore some of the drawbacks of using English-only as a sales medium, check out some creative solutions, and consider what this all means for global app development.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>