<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Technology on Rotational Labs</title><link>https://rotational.io/tags/technology/</link><description>Recent content in Technology on Rotational Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 06:10:14 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rotational.io/tags/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>In Which an English Major Interns in Tech</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/english-major-interns-in-tech/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 06:10:14 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/english-major-interns-in-tech/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Over the course of the past few months, I’ve had the pleasure of interning at Rotational Labs as a technical writer. I’m excited to share a little bit about my experience and provide some insight from the perspective of someone who is entering the world of distributed systems for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>A History of the Cloud and Where It's Going Next</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/cloud-generations/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 15:32:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/cloud-generations/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no doubt public cloud providers have transformed the technology landscape; in this post we retrace the evolution of the cloud to gather clues into where the industry is headed next.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Why UX Will Get Worse Before it Gets Better</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/ux-whats-missing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 17:20:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/ux-whats-missing/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The things we make are not user-friendly by accident; we have to &lt;em&gt;make&lt;/em&gt; them that way. And that&amp;rsquo;s hard. For most of the time people have been making things, we&amp;rsquo;ve been mainly concerned with making them user-friendly for just &lt;em&gt;us&lt;/em&gt;. And, even if the last few decades of app development have brought more focus to the importance of empathy (especially if it helps you capture market share), the last few years have forced app developers to acknowledge the continued pervasiveness of white privilege, gender privilege, and class privilege in UI/UX. Unfortunately, as our efforts to become more intentional and empathetic as technologists continue in the coming years, there is another problem we have barely considered that will become a major threat to compassionate, egalitarian, and even subversive app development. Spoiler: it&amp;rsquo;s our cloud infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>