<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Data Science on Rotational Labs</title><link>https://rotational.io/tags/data-science/</link><description>Recent content in Data Science on Rotational Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 15:01:46 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rotational.io/tags/data-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Guts, Glory, and Statistics: My Summer Internship at Rotational</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/intuition-and-statistics/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 15:01:46 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/intuition-and-statistics/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;While not always rational (or even helpful) our intuition fundamentally shapes how we think. In this post, summer intern Julie illustrates how she uses statistics to keep her analyses grounded, and how that translates to business value.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Let The Right One In: Model Selection for the AI Era</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/pick-the-best-ai/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 09:48:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/pick-the-best-ai/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no &amp;ldquo;best AI model for all use cases.&amp;rdquo; You have to do the science each time. If you&amp;rsquo;re new to experimental design for AI/ML, here&amp;rsquo;s a quick and dirty intro to the &lt;strong&gt;Model Selection Triple&lt;/strong&gt; methodology.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>How to Build a Real-Time Model to Predict Flight Delays</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/real-time-flight-delays/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 14:58:48 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/real-time-flight-delays/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever tried to build a model that can handle new data in real time? We set out to do just that, and discovered that there aren&amp;rsquo;t a lot of tutorials about training real-time machine learning models, so we made this one!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Rotational Announces Partnership, Hackathon with the University of Chicago Data Science Institute</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/uchicago-hackathon/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 08:04:58 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/uchicago-hackathon/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Rotational Labs is excited to announce our partnership with the &lt;a href="https://datascience.uchicago.edu/"&gt;University of Chicago Data Science Institute&lt;/a&gt;, including co-hosting a hackathon to help students learn to apply real-time data science techniques to real-world problems.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>How to Dockerize Python Data Science Processes</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/how-to-dockerize-data-science-processes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 11:52:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/how-to-dockerize-data-science-processes/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Docker is great, but most tutorials are geared toward devOps users, not data scientists. If you&amp;rsquo;re building long-running processes for NLP, ML, or generative AI, here&amp;rsquo;s a blueprint for Python Docker containers for data science!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>