<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Python on Rotational Labs</title><link>https://rotational.io/tags/python/</link><description>Recent content in Python on Rotational Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 12:00:55 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rotational.io/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building Real-Time Apps in Python with Ensign and Streamlit</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/ensign-streamlit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 12:00:55 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/ensign-streamlit/</guid><description>&lt;p>Python may be the 2nd best language for everything, but it&amp;rsquo;s a favorite of data scientists worldwide, and delivers a world of functionality. Did you know you can even build customer-facing AI/ML apps with Python now? Learn how&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>PubSub 101 - Using the PyEnsign SDK</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/pubsub-101---using-the-python-sdk/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 08:05:14 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/pubsub-101---using-the-python-sdk/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Python SDK is the most popular way to use Ensign. In this module you will write some Python code to publish data to your project.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reinforcement Learning, Automation... and Tetris</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/reinforcement-learning-automation-and-tetris/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 11:46:04 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/reinforcement-learning-automation-and-tetris/</guid><description>&lt;p>Every time I&amp;rsquo;m writing complex rules in my code, I remember there&amp;rsquo;s a machine learning technique for this: Reinforcement Learning. RL models are able to learn the optimal rules given predefined rewards. Read on to learn how!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Welcome to Ensign U!</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/welcome-to-ensign-u/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 12:41:46 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/welcome-to-ensign-u/</guid><description>&lt;p>Like any new tool, Ensign takes a little time to learn. But take it from us (a bunch of seasoned data science experts) &amp;ndash; it will open up a new world of data science applications for you. Check out this beginner-friendly introduction!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Spooky `asyncio` Errors and How to Fix Them</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/spooky-asyncio-errors-and-how-to-fix-them/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2023 10:44:23 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/spooky-asyncio-errors-and-how-to-fix-them/</guid><description>&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;ve heard the &lt;code>asyncio&lt;/code> library unlocks concurrency for Python with minimal syntactical overhead, but the terminology makes you tremble! Don&amp;rsquo;t panic — here are 3 of the most common errors you will encounter and how to fix them.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rotational Announces Partnership, Hackathon with the University of Chicago Data Science Institute</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/uchicago-hackathon/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 08:04:58 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/uchicago-hackathon/</guid><description>&lt;p>Rotational Labs is excited to announce our partnership with the &lt;a href="https://datascience.uchicago.edu/">University of Chicago Data Science Institute&lt;/a>, including co-hosting a hackathon to help students learn to apply real-time data science techniques to real-world problems.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to Dockerize Python Data Science Processes</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/how-to-dockerize-data-science-processes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 11:52:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/how-to-dockerize-data-science-processes/</guid><description>&lt;p>Docker is great, but most tutorials are geared toward devOps users, not data scientists. If you&amp;rsquo;re building long-running processes for NLP, ML, or generative AI, here&amp;rsquo;s a blueprint for Python Docker containers for data science!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Intro to Polars: A Pandas Alternative for Efficiently Working with Large Datasets</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/introduction-to-polars/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 09:32:37 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/introduction-to-polars/</guid><description>&lt;p>Dataframes are a powerful data structure for data processing, analytics, and ML. For many years, Pandas has been my go-to. But it can really slow you down when you&amp;rsquo;re working with big or high-dimensional data. Enter Polars!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>