<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on Rotational Labs</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on Rotational Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 15:01:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rotational.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Finding the Sweet Spot: What Our Qualitative Data Reveals About AI Coding Tools</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/what-qualitative-data-reveals-about-ai-coding-tools/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 06:57:40 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/what-qualitative-data-reveals-about-ai-coding-tools/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In the first installment of this &lt;a href="blog/do-ai-coding-assistants-help/"&gt;internal study&lt;/a&gt;, we described the six-month study we conducted this past year to better understand how AI coding assistants impacted the team at Rotational.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>AI and Learning Debt: How to Use AI to Make Yourself Smarter - Not Dumber</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/ai-and-learning-debt/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 17:13:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/ai-and-learning-debt/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This is a post about how to use AI to make yourself smarter - not dumber.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>AI Agents and Tools: Unlocking Business Impact</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/ai-agents-and-tools/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 09:45:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/ai-agents-and-tools/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="tools-how-ai-agents-get-real-work-done"&gt;Tools: How AI Agents Get Real Work Done&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we’ve covered &lt;a href="https://rotational.io/blog/ai-agents-defined/"&gt;AI agents&lt;/a&gt; in general, and &lt;a href="https://rotational.io/blog/prompt-engineering-overview-key-to-steering-agents/"&gt;prompts&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://rotational.io/blog/making-sense-of-llms/"&gt;LLMs&lt;/a&gt; specifically, let’s move on to &lt;strong&gt;tools&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>What We’ve Learned From 3 Months Living with AI Coding Tools</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/do-ai-coding-assistants-help/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 16:11:26 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/do-ai-coding-assistants-help/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We spent three months testing two AI coding assistants across our team of six. So far we&amp;rsquo;ve learned that overdelegation backfires, well-scoped tasks help, and accelerating an individual ≠ accelerating a team.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Making Sense of LLMs</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/making-sense-of-llms/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 09:45:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/making-sense-of-llms/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Now that we’ve covered &lt;a href="https://rotational.io/blog/ai-agents-defined/"&gt;agents at a high level&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://rotational.io/tags/prompt-engineering/"&gt;prompts&lt;/a&gt; specifically, let’s move to the next component in our series: &lt;strong&gt;Large Language Models (LLMs)&lt;/strong&gt;, a key subset of generative AI. In an agentic framework, LLMs serve as the “brain” or decision-execution component of the agent.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Prompts: The Key to Steering Agents</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/prompt-engineering-overview-key-to-steering-agents/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 09:46:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/prompt-engineering-overview-key-to-steering-agents/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;AI agents have the ability to complete tasks autonomously, but without clear, well-structured prompts, they stumble. Prompt engineering helps bridge the gap between potential and performance.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Guts, Glory, and Statistics: My Summer Internship at Rotational</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/intuition-and-statistics/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 15:01:46 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/intuition-and-statistics/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;While not always rational (or even helpful) our intuition fundamentally shapes how we think. In this post, summer intern Julie illustrates how she uses statistics to keep her analyses grounded, and how that translates to business value.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>AI Agents Defined: Practical, Probabilistic, and Purposeful</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/ai-agents-defined/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 11:26:38 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/ai-agents-defined/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;AI agents represent a significant opportunity for businesses, provided they&amp;rsquo;re designed for real business impact. This potential has become especially viable as cost-efficient reasoning models become increasingly accessible. While there&amp;rsquo;s no single standard definition, here&amp;rsquo;s our perspective.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Let The Right One In: Model Selection for the AI Era</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/pick-the-best-ai/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 09:48:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/pick-the-best-ai/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no &amp;ldquo;best AI model for all use cases.&amp;rdquo; You have to do the science each time. If you&amp;rsquo;re new to experimental design for AI/ML, here&amp;rsquo;s a quick and dirty intro to the &lt;strong&gt;Model Selection Triple&lt;/strong&gt; methodology.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Underappreciated Art of Capturing Novel Data</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/capturing-novel-data/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 10:25:02 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/capturing-novel-data/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;While the internet is an endless source of free data, everyone is training on the same tired datasets, and they’ve likely got more years of practice. Building a novel dataset tailored to your problem can be a game-changer (if done right).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The AI Paradox: Why More Technology Means More Humanity</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/why-employees-must-remain-in-the-loop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 11:40:43 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/why-employees-must-remain-in-the-loop/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;AI is rapidly transforming the workplace, but don&amp;rsquo;t be fooled into thinking it&amp;rsquo;s as simple as replacing workers. If you want to stay ahead of the curve, try a human-centered approach.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Could Disposable UI Solve Data Science's Low ROI Problem?</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/rise-of-disposable-ui/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 11:58:27 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/rise-of-disposable-ui/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Data scientists often struggle to deliver impact in production because they work in notebooks, outside the application stack. Could GenAI tools for UI creation help solve the low ROI problem in data science?&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Is Shame Sabotaging Your AI Journey?</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/shame-and-automation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 07:07:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/shame-and-automation/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Workplace AI adoption can be hindered by unexpected human factors, including employee shame. In this post, an AI expert recounts real-world examples of overcoming these barriers to unlock a virtuous cycle of human-centered innovation.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>How Custom AI Systems Return on Investment</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/how-rotational-does-ai/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 09:41:25 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/how-rotational-does-ai/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;AI hype often outpaces real results, especially for mid-market companies, because standalone models fall short. The key to success is a system-based approach. Read on to learn how to build custom AI solutions that return on investment.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>How to Build AI Applications In Minutes With Transformers.js</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/how-to-build-ai-applications-in-minutes-with-transformersjs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 12:09:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/how-to-build-ai-applications-in-minutes-with-transformersjs/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Creating AI applications is easier than ever these days, especially in JavaScript. Discover how you can build your own in only a few minutes with Transformers.js!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Rotational Joins EU-US Data Privacy Framework to Strengthen Privacy Commitment</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/rotational-joins-eu-us-data-privacy-framework-to-strengthen-privacy-commitment/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 15:17:41 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/rotational-joins-eu-us-data-privacy-framework-to-strengthen-privacy-commitment/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Rotational has joined the US-EU Data Privacy Framework, reinforcing its commitment to privacy in an era of growing data-driven innovation and generative AI.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Taming the Meeting Monster: Boost Your Efficiency with AI Notetaking</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/taming-the-monster-with-ai/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 09:00:09 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/taming-the-monster-with-ai/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Life in a startup is a balancing act, with meetings the weights threatening to tip the scales. PMs must translate complex discussions into clear action items and make sure nothing slips through the cracks. Here&amp;rsquo;s my secret weapon.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Product Development in the AI Era</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/product-development-in-the-ai-era/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 08:55:54 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/product-development-in-the-ai-era/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Last month, we spoke to a panel of expert product managers who have successfully implemented AI solutions in their organizations. This post recaps some of the key strategies and insights they shared.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>HMAC Verification Tokens</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/hmac-verification-tokens/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 14:27:01 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/hmac-verification-tokens/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In this post, we explore sending a secure message to a user that doesn&amp;rsquo;t have an account on your system and therefore cannot be authenticated. We&amp;rsquo;ll explore the use of HMAC verification tokens that you can email to a recipient as a single-use access code for a specific message or document.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Recapping PyTorch: Key Takeaways from the 2024 Conference</title><link>https://rotational.io/blog/pytorch-conference-2024/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 14:25:57 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://rotational.io/blog/pytorch-conference-2024/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I spent last week in San Francisco meeting up with the Rotational team to attend &lt;a href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/pytorch-conference/"&gt;PyTorch Conference&lt;/a&gt;. If you&amp;rsquo;re an LLM developer and didn&amp;rsquo;t make it this year, here are some of my key highlights and takeaways.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>