<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Rotational Labs</title>
    <link>https://rotational.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Rotational Labs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; 2021 Rotational Labs, LLC, All Rights Reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 15:01:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rotational.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why WebAssembly Is the Future of Computing</title>
      <link>https://rotational.io/blog/webassembly-the-future-of-computing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 08:51:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rotational.io/blog/webassembly-the-future-of-computing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you talk about WebAssembly (WASM), you just may spark debate about whether it is really the next best thing in web development or the second coming of Java applets. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll dive into WASM, how it is currently transforming web development, and why we think its future is so bright.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Eventing Platform Landscape</title>
      <link>https://rotational.io/blog/eventing-platforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 12:28:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rotational.io/blog/eventing-platforms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kafka and PubSub and Kinesis, oh my! Which eventing platform is best? In this post we&amp;rsquo;ll explore the three primary categories of eventing systems and understand their similarities, differences, and key use cases.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ranges of Integer Data Types</title>
      <link>https://rotational.io/blog/ranges-of-integer-data-types/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 09:40:12 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rotational.io/blog/ranges-of-integer-data-types/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The data type choices we make when building data systems or metrics is critically important: as our systems run for long periods of time it can be easy to overflow the integers that we use (Y2K bug anyone?). As a result, I find myself constantly checking the sizes of standard int types but I haven&amp;rsquo;t found a good way to Google this. This blog post is a quick reference for the standard sizes and a discussion on why it matters.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Which an English Major Interns in Tech</title>
      <link>https://rotational.io/blog/english-major-interns-in-tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 06:10:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rotational.io/blog/english-major-interns-in-tech/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the course of the past few months, I’ve had the pleasure of interning at Rotational Labs as a technical writer. I’m excited to share a little bit about my experience and provide some insight from the perspective of someone who is entering the world of distributed systems for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effective Programmers Read Code</title>
      <link>https://rotational.io/blog/effective-programmers-read-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 08:10:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rotational.io/blog/effective-programmers-read-code/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As programmers, we tend think of ourselves as &lt;em&gt;authors&lt;/em&gt; of code, but our daily engineering practice probably requires us to spend more time reading code than writing it. Perhaps this is even a source of stress for you. Changing your mindset to think of yourself as an avid code &lt;em&gt;reader&lt;/em&gt; may not only alleviate this anxiety, but also make you a more effective programmer, capable of architecting complex mental maps of code, a technique I refer to as &amp;ldquo;building the glass castle&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transparently Mocking gRPC Services</title>
      <link>https://rotational.io/blog/transparently-mocking-grpc-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 09:32:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rotational.io/blog/transparently-mocking-grpc-services/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;gRPC is an effective way of implementing service-to-service APIs. However, there are limited tools available for mocking and testing gRPC services out of the box. One option is to set up a live test server, although this comes with its own challenges and costs. In this blog post we will demonstrate a more lightweight solution using the &lt;code&gt;bufconn&lt;/code&gt; package and a hand-built mock. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, this is easier than it seems!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five Technologies Quietly Transforming the Web</title>
      <link>https://rotational.io/blog/five-technologies-quietly-transforming-the-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 13:00:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rotational.io/blog/five-technologies-quietly-transforming-the-web/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With almost 30 billion connected devices, this isn’t Al Gore’s internet anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider this: According to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/solutions/collateral/executive-perspectives/annual-internet-report/white-paper-c11-741490.html&#34;&gt;Cisco’s Annual Internet Report&lt;/a&gt;, there will be 29.3 billion internet-connected devices in 2023, or more than three for every human. The internet has no doubt transformed society and industry, while proving to be resilient and scalable. It also continues to evolve.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6 Things You Didn&#39;t Realize about Crypto</title>
      <link>https://rotational.io/blog/six-things-you-didnt-know-about-crypto/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 09:53:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rotational.io/blog/six-things-you-didnt-know-about-crypto/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a distributed systems company, we’ve had the privilege of speaking with dozens of vendors building crypto-adjacent solutions over the past few years. We’ve learned a lot along the way, especially about some of the key misconceptions that continue to challenge builders, users, investors, and other crypto stakeholders.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marshaling Go Enums to and from JSON</title>
      <link>https://rotational.io/blog/marshaling-go-enums-to-and-from-json/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 08:50:04 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rotational.io/blog/marshaling-go-enums-to-and-from-json/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Customizing JSON serialization for your data types seems relatively straightforward on the surface, but it&amp;rsquo;s easy to get turned around in receiver, value, pointer, and indirection confusion. Many of the patterns and rules-of-thumb you use in your normal Go code can lead you astray. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll illustrate exactly how and why to handle these edge cases.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Achieving Total Ordering With CRDTs</title>
      <link>https://rotational.io/blog/achieving-total-ordering-with-crdts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 15:02:21 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rotational.io/blog/achieving-total-ordering-with-crdts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Conflict-free replicated data types (or &amp;ldquo;CRDTs&amp;rdquo;) are inspiring the creation of more collaborative applications and improving the experience of users of distributed systems. In this post, we will explore how these data structures can be used to achieve a consistent, total ordering of events across many peers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
